- All right,
Speaker 1: welcome back. As the graphic says, there've been a lot of fast developments this evening on the debt ceiling standoff. If you're just catching up, here's where things stand. President Biden meeting this afternoon with top congressional leaders, resulting in no breakthrough for a deal. Not surprisingly, each side seems to be pointing fingers at one another. President Biden did
Speaker 2: speak at the White House about the lack of progress a little bit
earlier.
I told
Speaker 3: congressional leaders that I'm prepared to begin a separate discussion about my budget and the spending priorities,
but not
Speaker 3: under the threat of default. As
I said, I've
Speaker 3: already cut the deficit by $1.7 trillion in my first two years in office. But in the meantime, in the meantime, we need to take the threat of default off the table. Now,
both
Speaker 4: sides have said they will meet again on Friday,
Speaker 1: but really we're in a race against the clock. Joining
us now
Speaker 1: is California Congressman.
Ro
Speaker 1: Khanna, Congressman Khanna, great to have you back on again. Listen, Mitch McConnell said we're not going to default. The president said we don't want to default. Are we going to get a deal?
Well, I believe we're
Speaker 5: going to pay our bills, and I don't think we're going to default. It would be catastrophic. It would be a self-inflicted wound on the greatest economy in the world. Why would we want to do that? Pay our bills, and then let's discuss, honestly, how to reduce the deficit.
Speaker 6: I mean, let's talk about repealing some of Trump's
Speaker 6: tax cuts on the very wealthy. Let's talk about repealing some of George W. Bush's tax cuts on the very wealthy. Let's talk about scrapping the cap on Social Security after $250,000. Let's talk about certain defense cuts so we don't have a trillion-dollar defense. I've just put a number of proposals on the table, and we can have that conversation after we pay our bills.
Speaker 7: Give us one or two of your key proposals. If
Speaker 1: you sat down in a room with Speaker McCarthy, maybe you have. You're both Californians, after all. What are your proposals?
i'm willing to sit
Speaker 8: down with him and i have
Speaker 9: before we worked on legislation here's one thing i think bipartisan we could get behind you know the people who got some of the covid money who should not have qualified for it multi-million dollar firms that basically
Speaker 5: gamed the system why don't we audit everyone who took those covid loans and make sure they actually qualified that would start that'd be a start i'm
Speaker 10: not sure you want to do that congressman because you may not like what you find. You can search who took COVID money on its public data and
Speaker 10: And I don't know if you want to do that. Well,
look, I
Speaker 9: mean, I'm all for the mom and pop shops getting it. But if you're a multimillion dollar business and you got COVID funding
Speaker 11: and you didn't qualify, I mean, that should be money coming back to the taxpayers. There's a lot more that I want in terms of repealing some of the
Speaker 12: top tax cuts for the very wealthy on that Trump had and Bush had. But those are going to be more contentious. But the COVID money that went out to people
Speaker 11: who didn't deserve it, that should be bipartisan.
We
Speaker 1: talk a lot about debt forgiveness. Most of it's coming in the form of talking about student loan debt forgiveness. Now, it's very popular among people with student loans. I'm not sure if it's very popular among people without student loans or the blue collar. You're talking about killing health care debt, are
you
Speaker 13: not? Like getting rid of that type of debt for whom and how would this work, Congressman?
There are a lot
Speaker 14: of people,
Speaker 12: they're insured, they have a stay in the hospital, and, you know, you break a bone, you have a car accident, and then they find out that their own insurance covered 80%, 90%, which may sound good, until you find out you've got a $200,000 bill, and you're left with $10,000, $20,000, $30,000 of debt. And a lot of people have this debt, and it keeps accumulating with credit card payments, and what we're saying is no one in America should go into debt.
Speaker 12: for falling
Speaker 6: sick I don't think that that's hard to do people say well who's going to pay for it I mean we pay as a society for our roads in this country for our public schools I think the richest country in the world where my district
Speaker 12: has 10 trillion dollars of market value can say we'll pay to make sure no one goes into medical debt in America
who
Speaker 1: covers that cost that I guess is the question if you wipe out the debt somebody's not getting
paid
Speaker 1: Hospitals, churras.
-
Speaker 15: Sure, there's about $89 billion of medical debt in this country.
Speaker 12: And my view is that we should first stop the price gouging of hospitals and make sure that there's not aggressive debt collection, but then we should set up a federal fund for those hospitals to be able to be compensated for the legitimate debt.
Speaker 12: I'm very open that I think it should be the taxpayers that are paying for the medical debt for people. But I just think as a society, we shouldn't have people going into debt. I think it's wrong. I don't
Speaker 6: think if—there, by the grace of God, go all of us. I mean, if someone has an
Speaker 16: accident, if someone gets sick, if someone gets cancer, it's bad enough you're in the hospital.
I
Speaker 18: had some people very close to me who went through some of the things
Speaker 13: that you just mentioned as well. But how do we just bring the, how can we bring the cost of medical care down? I literally went in to see an, I had a sinus infection. It's a true story. I went in and got a nose scan. He prescribed me some spray. I was in there maybe 12 minutes. I just got the bill. It was $1,084. Why? Why?
Well, I would
Speaker 19: recommend American sickness.
Speaker 2: You're going to prescribe me an anxiety drug now because I got the bill. I mean, it's ridiculous. I
agree with
Speaker 20: you. Now, we may disagree, but I think Medicare for all would actually lower costs because
Speaker 12: you'd be taking out the hospital facility fees. You'd be taking out all of the private insurance profits. You'd be taking out the excessive profits of pharma. And we also have technology solutions that can reduce costs. But look, we pay 20% of our GDP in health care costs. It's what's led to wage stagnation. It's what led to some of the offshoring of manufacturing. We need to figure out how we get some of the excessive costs out of the system. Congressman
Ro
Speaker 21: Khanna of California, really appreciate it. Thank you, sir. Be well. Thank
Speaker 12: you.